Praveen Ragipani ragipani.praveen06@gmail.com (218) 430-1512

http://praveen.ten-xlabs.com

Professional Summary:

Over all 9 years of professional experience in Applications design, Development, Integration, Maintenance, Installation, Implementation, testing of various client/server, N-tier and web application and its design, using various UI- Technologies.

- Good experience on CSS background, layouts, Positioning, Animation, Borders, Padding, Tables, Pseudo classes and Pseudo elements.
- Front end/UI/Web/Mobile development experience with HTML,HTML5, CSS, CSS3, Bootstrap,JavaScript,jQuery,AJAX,JSON,TypeScript,ReactJs,Redux,Flux,Angular 4, Angular JS, ES5& ES6, Node js, vue js and Browserify/Common JS patterns.
- Experience in working with Bootstrap for Responsive Web design. Worked with SASS preprocessor.
- Experienced as a User Interface/User Experience (UI/UX) Developer in developing applications using HTML/HTML5, CSS/CSS3 and Various JavaScript Frameworks.
- Strong experience in JavaScript MVC frameworks React, Angular JS and Angular IO. Deep understanding in the development of view layers using React library.
- Good experience in PHP and its frameworks Wordpress and Laravel.
- Experienced with Components, Directives, Data binding, Custom Pipes, Services, Dependency Injection, Routing and Retrieving Data using HTTP in Angular 2.0 and Typescript.
- Experience in Developing User Interface (UI) Rich Web Applications, and Web Service
 Applications using Front End/User Interface (UI) Technologies like Object Oriented JavaScript,
 Type Script, Angular 2.0, Angular 4, Angular 6, Angular 7, Karma, Node JS, React JS, Bootstrap,
 Media Queries, CSS Frameworks, Python, Django
- Experience in developing single page application (SPA) with Responsive design concept using different JavaScript and CSS frameworks like Angular 2.0, React, Polymer, Bootstraps and Foundation.
- Extensive experience in web and mobile apps development.
- Worked on CMS tools Wordpress, Joomla
- Experience of working on CSS Preprocessors like LESS and SASS along with JavaScript task runners like Grunt and bower.
- Expertise in maintaining complex rich web applications and understanding and modifying existing code.
- Experience of working with Docker, Nginx, AWS, EC2, Apache, Websphere, XAMP and MAMP
- Well versed with Software Development Life Cycle process which includes designing, developing, testing and implementation. Experience in using agile/scrum methodology, TDD.
- Experience in working with RESTFUL web services using POSTMAN and called Rest web services through Angular Js to get JSON objects and modified the response object to display on web pages.
- Extensive client-side and server-side Javascript development experience (eg. node.js, ES6, React, Angular)

- Good experience on package managers and build tools like yarn, gulp, webpack, bower, grunt.
- Experience in JavaScript build tools like Grunt/Gulp, Node, brew and web pack.
- Good knowledge on Angular 5 and 6.
- Designed & developed using HTML5, CSS3, EXT JS, JavaScript, XML, AngularJS, NodeJS, JSP, JSON, Vue.js, JSF, J2EE and Ajax.
- Experience of Database Administration, design, development, maintenance and production support of relational databases, business applications, new server setup, MySql Server installation, upgrade, migration.
- Full stack development experience working on webapps with many technologies: Angular, React, Node, GraphQL, MySQL.
- Good experience of JUnit testing and Javascript Testing frameworks.
- Good experience in using Log4J, JUnit for testing and Bitbucket, SVN, GIT for Version Control.

Work Experience

Pansophic Learnings (Remote)

Role: Sr. Full Stack Dev/ DevOps

Sep 2020 – Present

<u>Summary</u>: Worked on Interactive Learning Application to help admins teachers to manage subjects and add audible images to help kids learn interactively.

Responsibilities:

- Worked on UI to add features like managing users, subjects, metas. Adding text to speech recognitions (Using AWS Polly) for audible learnings
- Worked on completely serverless architecture.
- Knowledge of using flux architecture in **ReactJS** for building client side web application.
- Worked on Setting up CI/CD Pipelines using AWS Codestar.
- Worked on setting up new rest api using NodeJS

Environment: Node, AWS – Polly, CodeStart, EC2, ELB, Serverless, Nodejs, React, CloudFormation

R.Hollenshed (Maryland)

Role: Sr. Full Stack Developer

May 2016 - Aug 2020

<u>Summary</u>: Worked on Angular, Node, Python, PHP, Slim based application for Vehicle Pricing and Appraisal in which primary responsibilities include design and development of rate plan module for Online Account Management (OLAM).

Responsibilities:

- Developing a user interface application using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, Type Script, Angular 4, Angular 6, Angular 9, React and Node JS.
- Migrated code from Angular 4 to Angular 6.
- Expertise in using Angular 6 directives, Controllers, Filters, Services, Templates, Events and Injectors.
- Used LAMP stack for development.
- Created and Maintained HMVC Content Management System Website by using Laravel, jQuery, JavaScript, HTML, CSS.
- Developed additional UI Components using JSF and implemented an asynchronous,
 AJAX (JQuery) based rich client to improve customer experience.
- Developed UI components for email and link sharing of documents and files for a Content. Management System using Backbone.js and JQuery.
- Implemented Restful API using Laravel and CI to enable the partner's price estimations.
- Implemented a Node.js server to manage authentication.
- Implemented various screens for the front end using React.js
- Worked over Hybrid app development using Phonegap and AngularJS.
- Worked on writing test using KarmaJS.
- Involved in Agile software development life cycle (SDLC) with SCRUM methodology.
- Migrated from Angular 1 to Angular 4/5. Worked with Angular directives, components, and services.
- Used JavaScript DOM manipulation and JavaScript event to generate the data result in UI.
- Developed test scripts for service calls and rendered data through XML files.
- Implemented JWT token based authentication for the REST API.
- Designed and implemented sharable and re-usable software service API's.
- Involved in site building and development of applications based on Angular, PHP, Laravel.
- Deployed developed code to all the environments.
- Worked closely with cross-functional teams (QA, BA, PM, Product Owner) as a part of AGILE environment.
- Maintenance of applications in all the environments.
- Experience with Front-end JavaScript frameworks like Angular JS, Node JS. And with the creation of RESTful Web service.
- Worked with GIT Version control.
- Worked with mocha, Jasmine for unit tests for the application
 Environment: PHP/Laravel, HTML5/HTML, CSS3/CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, JSON, Phonegap, AngularJS, Angular 4/5, Node.js, React, Web pack 2.0, MVC, SVN, AJAX, XML, Eclipse, MongoDB, MySQL.
- Prudential Financial (Fairfax VA)

Role: Sr. UI Developer June 2014 to April 2016

<u>Summary</u>: Worked on React, GraphQL based application in which users can manage their funds and easily move them by using transfer or rebalance.

Responsibilities:

- Developing a user interface application using HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, Angular 4 and Node JS.
- Worked with GIT Version control.
- Involved in Agile software development life cycle (SDLC) with SCRUM methodology.
- Configured continuous integration with Jenkins on Amazon EC2.
- Worked with Angular directives, components, and services.
- Used JavaScript DOM manipulation and JavaScript event to generate the data result in UI.
- UI Screens were developed using HTML5, Java Scripts, Ajax, JQuery, Custom-tags, react.js and CSS3.
- Assisted in migrating from a legacy REST-based backend to one based on GraphQL.
- Developed a few modules using Python on Django including Tastypie Web Framework.
- Used ANGULAR JS and consumed Restful Web Services which are created out of Node API. Good understanding in implementing web applications using Angular JS framework.
- Developed dynamic responsive Web Application by integrating Angular2 with Bootstrap which is further integrated with Web Services and Vue.js.
- Optimized Microservices using NodeJS and ES6 as interfaces to NoSQL database.

Environment: Java, HTML5, CSS2/3, Laravel, JavaScript, JQuery, JSON, Angular.js, Node.js, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, React.js, Redux, JSP, AJAX, SOAP, XML, Oracle, Windows.

Wells Fargo (Fairfax VA)

Role: Software Developer December 2012 to May 2014

Summary: Worked on Mico Angular application which runs on Openfin as a separate native app which is used by Agents to get real time pricing updates.

Responsibilities:

- Developed user interface by using the AngularJS, Html and CSS.
- Install and configuring monitoring scripts for AWS EC2 instances and deployed project using Jenkins and using Web Services like Amazon Web Services (AWS).
- Extensively used Gitlab for version controlling and regularly pushed the code to it.
- Involved in Agile software development life cycle (SDLC) with SCRUM methodology.
- Involved in various stages of application development through requirement analysis, development, testing and deployment.
- Worked on AJAX controls like Update Panel to manage the post back of the web page to server, AJAX Script Manager and Script Manager Proxy controls to register JavaScript and web service files.

- Responsible for configuring, integrating, and maintaining all Development, QA, Staging and Production PostgreSQL/Dynamo databases within the organization.
- Worked for backward compatibility to support browsers like IE6, IE7 and IE8.

Environment: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, AJAX, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, DOM, PostgreSQL, XML, DHTML, JSON, SOAP, GIT, Jenkins and Windows.

• Innovativeway Inc. (Fairfax VA)

Role: UI Developer

September 2011 to November 2012

Summary: Worked on React, GraphQL based application in which we can create request/ticket and assign them to dev's. It's a Project Management Tool.

Responsibilities:

- Developing a user interface application using HTML, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript and developed a few modules over AngularJS.
- Developed stored procedures, triggers, functions and tables in MySQL database.
- Used the Mozilla Firefox extension, Firebug to view and debug HTML, DOM and JavaScript.
- Participated actively in fixing the bugs reported in Test, UAT and Production environments.
- Created Github repository for code collaboration and worked on JIRA issue management to track Sprint Cycles.
- UI Screens were developed using HTML, Java Scripts, Ajax, JQuery, Custom-tags, AngularJS and CSS.

Educational Details:

Bachelors of Computer Science (2007-2011) from RGTU, Bhopal